Guide to the Diaries (Miscellaneous) Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Diaries (Miscellaneous) collection
1681-1945
MS 181
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12.75
(28 boxes)
An artificial collection of diaries relating to Connecticut and other states and regions in the United States. Topics including farming, religion, military life, student life, travel, and the weather are documented.
Existence and Location of Copies
The Michael F. Campbell diary is also available on microfilm (290 frames on 1 reel, 35 mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM212.
Arrangement
The diaries are arranged alphabetically by diarist name, beginning with anonymous entries, and assigned sequential numbers which appear in the folder column for boxes 1-18. The remainder of the diaries are also assigned sequential numbers, however, there is no alphabetical order.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of miscellaneous diaries which are not part of any other collection.
All diaries, except those by anonymous writers, are catalogued. Cards are filed in the catalogue under author, subject, and geographical location.
Agriculture; Armed Forces; Business; Clergy; Education; Medicine; Shipping; Students -- Attitudes; Women; Asia; Connecticut -- Social life and customs; Connecticut; Europe -- Description and travel; Europe; Germany; Middle West; New England; New Haven (Conn.); New York (State); Southern States; United States -- Description and travel; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; Diaries; United States. Army ( Military life); Yale University -- Students
- [Anonymous], Manuscript Autobiography of an Unidentified 18th-Century Woman Residing in the Vicinity of East Granby, Connecticut, Circa 1700-1799 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- [Anonymous], A Journal of a Fue [sic] Days at York, 1741 October 10 - November 26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- [Anonymous], Diary and Account Book of a Farmer-Merchant, 1803-1809 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- [Anonymous], "Reise nach Italien im Herbst 1819" (Box 1, Folder 4)
- [Anonymous], Diary of an Itinerant Book Peddler Describing a Journey from Providence to Cazenovia, New York, Circa 1820 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- [Anonymous], Records of Sermons Preached in the Church at Harwinton, Connecticut, and a Record of Deaths in Harwinton, 1847-1853 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- [Anonymous], Diary and Commonplace Book, kept in Hamden, Connecticut, 1857-1863 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- [Anonymous], Diary of a Storekeeper in the Vicinity of New Haven, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- [Anonymous], Diary of a Storekeeper in the Vicinity of New Haven, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- [Anonymous], Diary of a Seven Week Trip Through Connecticut, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- [Anonymous], Diary of a Schoolteacher in the Vicinity of New Haven, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- [Anonymous], Diary of a Thirty-Three-Year-Old Housewife of Haddam, Connecticut, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- [Anonymous], Diary of a Twelve-Year-Old, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- [Anonymous], Diary and Account Book of a Farmer in the Vicinity of New Preston, New Milford, or Marbledale, Connecticut, 1908-1917 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bacon, George W., Diary listing the work and social activities of a farmer, Durham, Connecticut, 1846-1856 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Bee, Jacob (1664-), Diary (copy) consisting mainly of vital statistics in St. Margaret's Parish, Durham, England, 1681-1706 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Beers, Henry (1792-1864), Diary of the daily events in the life of a farmer, and containing his comments on the progress of the Civil War, [Newtown, Connecticut], 1863 May 24 - 1864 November 24 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Blakeman, Samuel, Diary concerning farm work, Stratford, Connecticut, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Bradley, Phinehas S., Diary concerning his work in the tanyard of Isaac Gilbert of New Haven, and a brief visit to his family in Watertown, Connecticut, 1813 June 1 - 1816 April 16 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Bushnell, Sydney, Diary containing a daily account of farm work, Saybrook, Connecticut, 1835 January 1 - 1843 December 30 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Campbell, Michael F. (1860-), Diaries of events in his life, New Haven:
  - 1876 October 2 - 1878 December 3 (Box 2a, Folder 21)
  - 1879 November 6-1881 September 1 (Box 2a, Folder 22)
  - 1881 September 2-1882 April 27 (Box 2a, Folder 23)
  - 1882 May 1 - 1883 April 30 (Box 2a, Folder 24)
- Carleton, Thomas P., Diary recounting his personal activities and his work as a farmer and laborer, New Haven and various places, 1841 March 9 - 1903 July 1 (Box 2a, Folder 25)
- Clemons, Harry (1831-1887), Diary and account book of personal and farm entries, Bantam, Connecticut, 1860 April 1 - 1861 March 4, 1875, 1883, 1887-1897 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Colter, George, Diary of a voyage from Belfast, Ireland, to Quebec, 1834 May - Jul, 1842-1843 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Cowles, Mary Lavinia (18??-1889), Diary mainly of a trip to Hartford; a few entries for North Haven, Connecticut, 1850, 1873-1874 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Cowles, Orson (1801-1860), Diary of his activities as a minister, Woodstock, Connecticut, and various places. Includes biographical sketches of Orson Cowles and Giles H. Cowles., 1829-1858 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Dibble, Ebenezer (-1784), Diary (copy) of an ensign in the French and Indian Wars, Crown Point, New York. Copied by Theodore Salisbury Woolsey from the original in the library at Cornwall, Connecticut. Published in Papers and Addresses of the Society of Colonial Wars in the State of Connecticut, vol., pp. 311-329., 1759 May 27- December 1; 1762 May 27-November 10 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Dowd, Anna J., Diary commenting mainly on the weather, East Hartford, Connecticut, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- [Doolittle, John H.], Diaries kept by a member of the Connecticut infantry, 20th regiment, Co. B, possibly John H. Doolittle of Woodbury, various places, 1862, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
- Dresser, Albert H., Diary of personal entries, Unadilla, New York, and Ottumwa, Iowa, 1865 July 12 - 1866 June 9 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Dudley, Mary L., Diary of personal entries, Waterbury, Connecticut, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Durrie, George H. (1820-1863), Diary (copy) of personal entries by a New Haven artist, [New Haven], 1845 January 1 - 1846 July 1 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Ely, Heman (1775-1852), Diary (copy) of a trip through Europe, including Paris. Contains a description of the wedding of Napoléon I and Marie Louise., 1809-1810 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Fellows, Henry Parker (1848-1927), Diary of personal entries kept by a student at Yale, New Haven, Connecticut; Hudson, New York; and various places, 1868 January 1 - September 28 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Fitch, Elizabeth Lucia (Wooster) (1795-1821), Diary of personal entries begun at the age of six-and-a-half, New Haven, 1801 November 9 - 1805 March 12 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Fowler, Frederick Acley (1850-)
  - Time book for music lessons, New Haven, 1880-1881 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Journal listing daily records of music lessons given to pupils in New Haven, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Fowler, George H. (1822-1883)
  - Commonplace book, Hamden, Connecticut. Most of the inscriptions are by Fowler's wife, Mary Jane (Beecher) Fowler (1827-), 1846-1851 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Diaries of personal entries kept by a rubber overseer of New Haven
    - 1851-1855 (Box 4, Folder 43-45)
    - 1858 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - 1860-1862 (Box 4, Folder 47-50)
    - 1865-1868 (Box 4, Folder 51-54)
    - 1871 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - 1874 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - 1879-1880 (Box 4, Folder 57-58)
    - 1882 (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Fowler, Mary Elizabeth (Root) [Mrs. Frederick Acley Fowler] (1852-), Diary of personal entries, New Haven, 1907-1909 (Box 5, Folder 60)
- Fowler, Mary Jane (Beecher) [Mrs. George H. Fowler] (1827-)
  - Journal and notebook of personal entries, Hamden, Connecticut, and various places, 1862-1908 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Diary of personal reminiscences, Hamden, Connecticut. Two pages of data on boots are in the hand of Mrs. Fowler's husband, George H. Fowler, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Diary of personal entries, Hamden, Connecticut. Diary contains accounts by Mrs. Fowler's husband, George H. Fowler, 1854-1862, 1889-1890 (Box 5, Folder 63)
- Furlow, Tim, Diary of a soldier in the 4th Georgia Regiment during the Civil War, various places, 1862 May 10 - 1864 January 1 (Box 5, Folder 64)
- Grosvenor, Ebenezer (1788-1817), Diaries of personal entries, Pomfret, Connecticut, 1812 September 1 - December 7 (Box 5, Folder 65-66)
- [Harris, A. Holbrook], Diary, memorandum book and almanac, [Boston], 1857 (Box 5, Folder 67)
- Hawkins, Minnie L., Diaries of personal entries, Oxford, Connecticut
  - 1876-1880 (Box 6, Folder 68-71)
  - 1884 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - 1890 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - 1893 (Box 6, Folder 74)
- Holbrook, Mary G., Diary of personal entries, New Haven and Oxford, Connecticut, 1851 (Box 6, Folder 75)
- Holman, Lucia (Ruggles) (1793-1886), Journal of a voyage to the Sandwich Islands and residence there. This journal is in the form of letters from Mrs. Holman to her family. It is published in Bishop Museum, Special Publication, No. 17., 1819 November - 1820 September 18
  Existence and Location of Originals
  The original diary is owned by the Yale University Art Gallery and was returned to their Department of Indo-Pacific Art in 2018.
  Existence and Location of Copies
  The diary is available in digital form from Manuscripts and Archives.
- Hopkins, Edward (1845-), Diary of personal entries, Naugatuck, Connecticut, 1863 (Box 6, Folder 77)
- Hubbard, Samuel B., Diary of a sailor aboard the U.S. Steamer Augusts during the Civil War, 1862 November 3 - 1863 August 6 (Box 6, Folder 78)
- Huggins, William Sidney (1822-1862), Diary of a trip to Scotland and Europe, various places, 1846 (Box 6, Folder 79)
- Hutchins, Charles Josiah (1825-1887), Diary of personal entries kept by a minister, various places, 1852-1884 (Box 6, Folder 80)
- Johnson, Lucy F. (Hall) (1819-), Diaries of personal entries, New Haven
  - 1851-1853 (Box 6, Folder 81-83)
  - 1857 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - 1859 (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - 1861 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - 1863-1866 (Box 6, Folder 87-90)
  - 1868-1869 (Box 6, Folder 91-92)
  - 1870 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - 1873-1874 (Box 7, Folder 94-95)
  - 1876-1877 (Box 7, Folder 96-97)
  - 1879-1894 (Box 7, Folder 98-115)
- Johnson, Samuel, Memorandum book kept by a builder, New Haven, 1858 (Box 7, Folder 116)
- Killick, Richard Henry
  - "Journal of a residence and tour in the United States of America in the years 1836-1837," Diary kept by a resident of London, England (Box 7, Folder 117)
  - "Journal of a visit to New York by a resident of London, England," New York, [1837] February 21 (Box 7, Folder 118)
- King, Alexander (1749-1831), Diary and account book, various places,. Included is an account of naval action at Fort Ticonderoga in 1776. Added are the births of King's children, orders as selectman New Windsor, Connecticut, and payments to the First Society of East Windsor, 1776 June 24 - 1804 April 61776 (Box 7, Folder 119)
- Knous, Samuel, Business memorandum books kept by an armorer and munitions inspector, Springfield, Massachusetts
  - 1851-1854 (Box 7, Folder 120-123)
  - 1862-1864 (Box 7, Folder 124-126)
- Lake, James K., Diary kept by a resident of Albion, New York, while visiting his grandparents in Sharon, Connecticut,. Laid in are four bills of sale for tobacco and livestock, 1860 March - July (Box 8, Folder 127)
- [Lanman, John Trumbull (1820-18520], Journal of a voyage onboard the barque Condor from New York to Valparaiso, Chile, 1850 January 21 - March 14 (Box 8, Folder 128)
- [Little, Mr.], Journal of a trip from Colombia, Connecticut, to Avon, New York, 1831 May 24 - June 26 (Box 8, Folder 129)
- Lott, Abraham, Diary (copy) of a trip from Kinderhook, New York, to Albany. Original diary is in the Columbia County Historical Society, Kinderhook, New York., 1774 June - July 5 (Box 8, Folder 130)
- Loveland, George Henry, a resident of Middletown, Connecticut
  - Journal kept on board the ship Bald Eagle on a voyage from New York to San Francisco. Added are the journals of the author kept on board the ship Tuskina on three voyages from San Francisco to Puget Sound., 1852 December 18 - 1854 March 22 (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - Journal (copy) kept on board the ship Wild Pigeon on a voyage from New York around the world,. Added is the journal (copy) of the author kept on board the ship Bald Eagle on a voyage from New York to San Francisco. Copied from the original by the author and completed 1890, 1851 October 10 - 1853 April 13, 1890 January 29 (Box 8, Folder 132)
  - Journal (copy) kept on board the ship Tuskina on three voyages from San Francisco to Puget Sound and return. Added is the journal (copy) the author kept on board the ship Bald Eagle. Copied from the original by the author and completed., 1853 April 30 - 1854 July 10, 1890 January 29 (Box 8, Folder 133)
- Marks, James G. (1828-), Diaries of personal entries, East Oranby, Connecticut, and various places
  - 1858-1866 (Box 8, Folder 134-144)
  - 1867-1880 (Box 9, Folder 145-158)
  - 1881-1902 (Box 10, Folder 159-179)
- Account books, East Granby, Connecticut, and various places, 1852-1855, 1860-1870 (Box 11, Folder 180-183)
- Monroe, E. R., Diaries of personal entries, Branford, Connecticut, 1884, 1892, 1898, 1902 (Box 11, Folder 184-87)
- Monroe, Edison A., Diaries of personal entries, Branford and New Haven, 1882-1906 (Box 11, Folder 188-209)
- Morris, Josie (Clark), Diary of a trip to England and various places. Laid in are loose items and clippings from the diary., 1867 (Box 12, Folder 210)
- [Nichols, Mr.], Meteorological record and diary, Greenfield Hill, Connecticut. Laid in are loose notes., 1889-1890 (Box 12, Folder 211)
- Norton, Mrs. Emily M., Diary, notes, accounts, and other data of a trip to England and France, and various places, 1876 (Box 12, Folder 212)
- Keeler, Giles O. (1807-1889), Diary kept by a farmer, Monroe, Connecticut, 1854 April 3 - 1875 June 15 (Box 12, Folder 213)
- Page, Abbott Chandler (1856-1946), Diary of personal entries, Branford, Connecticut, 1877 (Box 12, Folder 214)
- Palmer, T. R., Extracts from a diary kept by a minister, North Branford, Connecticut, 1821-1866 (Box 12, Folder 215)
- Palmer, George, Diaries kept by an insurance agent, Branford, Connecticut, 1868-1894 (Box 12, Folder 216-221)
- [Palmer, Miss K. E. ], Diary of a stenographer, New Haven, 1895 (Box 12, Folder 222)
- Peck, Minnie C. (1857-), Diary of personal entries, Ansonia, Connecticut, 1876-1881 (Box 13, Folder 223)
- Pennant, David (-1841), Diary mainly of tours of exhibitions, museums, and mineralogical collections in England; and various places. Laid in are eight pieces of autograph memoranda and fifteen pieces of newspaper clippings., 1817 April 21 - 1819 April 26 (Box 13, Folder 224)
- Roberts, Arthur O., Diary of personal entries, East Hartford, Connecticut, 1864-1867 (Box 13, Folder 225)
- Root, George A., Diaries of personal entries, New Haven, 1876, 1882 (Box 13, Folder 226-227)
- Schaw, Janet (ca. 1731-ca. 1801), Journal of a journey from Scotland to the West Indies, North Carolina and Portugal; and various places. Published under the title of Journal of a Lady of Quality, by Evangeline and Charles MacLean Andrews, 1774-1776, 1921, 1934, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 228-229)
- [Scranton, Daniel Hubbard] (1826-), Diaries of personal entries mainly about the weather, Branford, 1860-1873 (Box 14, Folder 230-242)
- Scranton, Erastus (1771-1861), Memoranda of current events and diary of a minister in North Milford (now Oxford), Wolcott, and Burlington, Connecticut, and various places, 1805-1845 (Box 14, Folder 243)
- Searle, Morris W., Diary (typed copy) of the Journey and Adventures of the 52nd Massachusetts Regiment in Louisiana during the Civil War; and various places., 1862-1863 (Box 14, Folder 244)
- Sharpe, Mary A., Diary of personal entries of Mary A. Sharpe while a student at Grove Hall School, New Haven, including a personal expense account, 1865-1866 (Box 14, Folder 245)
- Skinner, Sophia, Diary of elderly New Haven widow referring mainly to her daughter Jennie [Mrs. William C. Dewey] and to deaths in the area, New Haven, 1895-1896 (Box 14, Folder 246)
- Smith, R. G., Diary of a housepainter and paper hanger of Meriden, Connecticut, 1891-1897 (Box 15, Folder 247)
- Spear, Sarah S. (Hall), fifteen diaries of personal entries, New Haven, 1855, 1862, 1873-1889 (Box 15, Folder 248-262)
- Stein, Oswald, Diaries of a German architect during the Second World War, including newspaper clippings, leaflets dropped by the Allies, letter photostats, and photographs [in German], Düsseldorf, Germany., 1943-1944 (Box 15, Folder 263-264)
- Stone, Rebecca Ward (1826-1885), Diary of young New Haven woman recording social engagements and all sermons delivered at Trinity Church, New Haven, 1845-1851 (Box 16, Folder 265)
- Tabb, Henry Wythe (1791-1863), Diary [carbon copy] of reminiscences and principal events in the life of a Virginia doctor, Auburn, Virginia., 1861 January 1 (Box 16, Folder 266)
- Tripp, Ephriam, Typed copy of journal of his service in the Continental Army during the American Revolution, Massachusetts and New York, 1775 April 19 - 1777 January 29 (Box 16, Folder 267)
- Tuttle, Edward M. (1849-f1.1928), Diaries of personal entries of a man living in Middletown, Connecticut, 1871-1875, 1891, 1895-1928 (Box 16, Folder 268-275)
- Tuttle, Mrs. Emerson, Diary of brief personal entries, near Southington, Connecticut, 1873 (Box 16, Folder 276)
- Van Deusen, John N. (1830-), Diaries of personal entries of a carpenter and machinist of West Winsted, New Haven, and other Connecticut towns, various places
  - 1852-1871 (Box 16, Folder 277-288)
  - 1872-1887 (Box 16A, Folder 289-299)
- Washburne, Elihu Benjamin (1816-1887), four diaries of personal entries and observations of events from various places during the Civil War and one pocket ledger, various places. Vols. 303 and 304 give eyewitness accounts of the Battle of the Wilderness and General Lee's surrender at Appomattox Court House., (1849-1952)1862-1865 (Box 17, Folder 300-304)
- Weed, Horatio Nelson (1812-), Diary and memorandum book of a Methodist minister in Guilford, Windsor Locks, Litchfield, Stepney, and various places in Connecticut, 1839-1859 (Box 17, Folder 305)
- Wheeler, Marvin (1819-), Diary of personal reflections of a young man from Bridgeport, Connecticut, relating primarily to his religious opinions, New York City and Bridgeport, Connecticut, 1837-1840 (Box 17, Folder 306)
- Williams, Henry C. (1841-), Diary (typed copy) of a young man from Oxford, Connecticut, while a member of Company E, 7th Regiment, Connecticut Volunteers during the Civil War, South Carolina and various places, 1863 January 1 - December 31 (Box 17, Folder 307)
- [Williams, Leroy Blanchard (1867-1945)], Journal of a trip to Europe, and various places, 1897 June 16 - October 7 (Box 17, Folder 308)
- Woods, Benjamin (1691-1758), Journal kept in Marlborough, Massachusetts, referring mainly to sermons preached by the Rev. Robert Breck, Wood's religious meditations, and deaths in the parish, 1726-1730 (Box 18, Folder 309)
- Steward, Ira R. (1795-), Autobiography of a New London minister, undated (Box 18, Folder 310)
- Clark, Kate (Upson) (1851-1935), Diaries, Diary of 1869 includes pamphlet, lectures, and informal talks by Mrs. Kate Upson Clark, 1868, 1869, 1890 (Box 18, Folder 311-312)
- Wickes, Simon Alexander (1806/7-1834), Diary (typed copy) kept by a Yale student, various places. Majority of entries describe a summer of study with Henry Dutton in Newton, Connecticut. Original in the possession of the Maryland Historical Society., 1825 July 4 - 1829 November (Box 19, Folder 314)
- Jarvis, Samuel Farmar (1786-1851), two diaries of a Yale Student, various places; one ledger, 1802-1803, 1813-1814 (Box 19, Folder 315-317)
- Unidentified diary of journey from Granville, Ohio, to Fairfax, Vermont, and return, 1823 (Box 19, Folder 318)
- Arvine, Earliss Porter (1846-1914), Diary kept as a Yale student, class of 1869 (Box 19, Folder 319)
  General note
  Transferred to Yale Misc. Manuscript Collection, MS 1258, Series I, Alphabetical
- Reade, William Churchill (1835-1908), Diary kept during his senior year at Yale College., 1863 January - November (Box 19, Folder 320)
- Crenshaw, W. L., "Journal in the South,"; "Ink Blots"; ms journal; funeral notice, 1852-1853, 1870 April 8 (Box 19, Folder 321)
- Cockran, Peter, Journal by Peter Cockran, 1812-13 and Signal and Instructions for Ships Under Convoy, Circa 1809-1813 (Box 19, Folder 322)
- Peck, David (1825-1874), Yale Class of 1849; diary, 1865 (Box 19, Folder 323)
- Denslou, Horace or Abner, Civil War soldier diary, 1864 (Box 19, Folder 324)
- [Numbers not assigned.] (Box 19, Folder 325-326)
- Wood, Mrs. Hartley, Personal diary, 1809-1811 (Box 19, Folder 327)
- Kemp, B., Commonplace book, [1818-1824?] (Box 19, Folder 328)
- Palgrave, William Gifford, Travel-journal of trip from London to Italy and back to the Rhine, some sketches, 1844 August - October (Box 19, Folder 329)
- Unidentified schoolteacher, Journal in Beaufort, South Carolina, and St. Augustine, Florida, in Portsmouth, Virginia., 1862 November - 1864 August (Box 20, Folder 330)
- Pratt, Peter, Yale Class of 1762, diary as a student, 1760-1762 (Box 20, Folder 331)
- Knight, John B., Journal of a trading voyage from Salem to islands in the Pacific and Indian Oceans aboard the brig Spy, 1832 August 8 - 1834 January 28 (Box 20, Folder 332)
- Unidentified Connecticut man, Journal fragment of trip in France and England, 1784 (Box 20, Folder 333)
- Williams, Dr. Charles M., Journal of a trip to Germany, 1914 September - May (Box 20, Folder 334)
- Rockwell, George, Diary, 1854-1855 (Box 20, Folder 335)
- Gager, Charles A., Journal of travels to Canary Islands, Spain, Jerusalem, with commonplace book and notes, 1836-1842
  - 1836-1842 (Box 20, Folder 336)
  - 1836-1842 (Box 29, Folder 336a)
- Rose, Israel Gurley (1799-1842), Yale Class of 1821, "A journal comprising some of the events which have occurred during the life of the writer." Covers the time from birth, 1818 April - 1823 January (Box 21, Folder 337-338)
- Peck, C.W., diary of a New Haven woman with an account of birth and death of "Kitty's" baby, 1883 (Box 21, Folder 339)
- Olmstead, John Howard (1820-1846), Yale Class of 1845, Journal of voyage to Europe and tour of Europe, 1841-1842 (Box 21, Folder 340)
- Goodell, Edwin Burpee (1851-1842), Yale Class of 1877, Montclair, New Jersey, lawyer and banker. Diaries and some engagement books, 1898-1942 (Box 21)
  - 1898-1902 November 5 (Box 21, Folder 341-344)
  - 1902 November-1918 April 7 (Box 22, Folder 345-353)
    General
    Includes engagement books, 1904-1908 (folder 348); 1909-1913 (folder 350); 1914-1918 (folder 352).
  - 1918 April 28-1930 November 9 (Box 23, Folder 354-358)
    Includes engagement book, 1920-1923 (folder 356).
  - 1930 November 23-1939 August 13 (Box 24, Folder 359-364)
    Includes engagement books, 1929-1933 (folder 359); 1934-1938 (folder 363).
  - 1939 August 20-1942 September 25 (Box 25, Folder 365-367)
    Includes engagement book, 1939-1942 (folder 365).
- Ford, Seabury (1801-1855), Yale Class of 1825, Ms diaries kept while a student at Yale College; eight volumes [numbers three and four wanting]. Includes a biographical essay by Mrs. W.R. Tuttle of Buchanan, Michigan
  - No.1, 1823 November 24-1824 January 1 (Box 26, Folder 368)
  - No.2, 1824 January-February 23 (Box 26, Folder 369)
  - No.5, 1824 June 15-September 1 (Box 26, Folder 370)
  - No.6, 1824 September 1-1825 January 12 (Box 26, Folder 371)
  - No.7, 1825 January 13-March 28 (Box 26, Folder 372)